SpongeBob, hurry up in there.
海绵宝宝，快点进去吧。
4,297 Krabby Patties
4,297 蟹肉饼
coming right up.
马上就来了。
Mm!
毫米！
Mm-mm.
嗯嗯。
Ahh.
啊。
Mm. Mm!
毫米。毫米！
Orders up.
订单上涨。
Ahh!
啊！
Spatty!
垃圾！
Hang in there, buddy.
坚持住，伙计。
I'll save you.
我会救你的。
Doink.
多因克。
Eeeh... no!
呃……不！
- Uh...
- Where's my Krabby Patty?
- 呃...
- 我的蟹黄饼在哪里？
- Yeah. What's taking so long?
- Ohh.
- 是的。什么事要花这么长时间？
- 哦。
SpongeBob.
Where are my orders? Huh?
海绵宝宝。
我的订单在哪里？啊？
I...I can't
flip patties anymore.
我……我不能
不再翻馅饼了。
You what?
你什么？
You better explain yourself,
boy-o.
你最好解释一下自己
男孩-o。
My spatula is broken,
Mr. Krabs.
我的锅铲坏了
蟹老板。
I can't make Krabby Patties
without Spatty.
我不会做蟹黄饼
没有斯帕蒂。
Is that all?
这就是全部吗？
Just grab another one
from the spatula closet.
再抓一张
从抹刀柜里。
Oh, I can't cook with those,
Mr. Krabs.
哦，我不能用这些做饭，
蟹老板。
I need to use my own spatula,
not just any spatula.
我需要用我自己的抹刀
不仅仅是任何抹刀。
You see, Mr. Krabs,
你看，蟹老板先生，
Spatty is very special
and very ancient.
斯帕蒂很特别
而且非常古老。
He was forged deep in the
mountains beyond the horizon
他被深深地锻造在
地平线之外的山脉
in the far-flung land of--
在遥远的土地上——
Listen up, boy-o.
听着，小伙子。
I'm losing money
by the second here.
我正在赔钱
到这里的第二个。
I don't care what you do,
我不在乎你做什么
but you better get back
in a jiffy
但你最好回去
一瞬间
or I'll just have to give
your job to SpongeTom here.
或者我只需要付出
你的工作就交给 SpongeTom 了。
I'm prepared.
我准备好了。
No, anything but that!
不，除了那个！
Don't worry.
I'll get my spatula reforged.
不用担心。
我会重新锻造我的铲子。
SpongeBob? Where are you--
海绵宝宝？你在哪 -
Hold down the fort for me,
Squidward. Thanks.
为我坚守堡垒，
章鱼哥。谢谢。
Ahh. Thank you.
啊。谢谢。
Huh, I've been using
them wrong all these years.
呵呵，我一直在用
这些年来他们都错了。
Ahh! Augh!
啊！啊啊！
Ohh!
哦！
The Mystical Misty Mountains.
神秘的迷雾山脉。
Finally here.
终于到了。
And now for a short walk
to the top.
现在步行一小段路
到顶部。
And... nyah!
还有……嗯！
Whew.
呼。
Eee! Ooh.
哎呀！哦。
Well, at least I didn't carry
this backpack for nothing.
还好，至少我没带
这个背包没什么用。
Huh?
啊？
Ahh!
- Amazing.
啊！
- 惊人的。
Right on time.
准时。
- I am?
- You sure are.
- 我是？
- 你确实是。
I'll be your guide today.
今天我将成为你的向导。
First up, we will cross this
amazing fish-made bridge.
首先，我们要跨越这个
令人惊叹的鱼桥。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
This is way easier
than it looks.
这更容易
比它看起来的要多。
Eh, eh, eh.
呃，呃，呃。
On your left is the chasm
of infinite bruising.
你的左边是鸿沟
无限的瘀伤。
Ohh. Isn't that wonderful?
哦。那不是很棒吗？
And on your right,
we got the freezing pit.
在你的右边，
我们得到了冰冻坑。
Eh, eh.
呃，呃。
I told you it'd be a breeze.
我告诉过你这会很容易。
You're doing amazing.
你做得很棒。
Let's keep moving.
让我们继续前进吧。
Oh. Well, here we are.
哦。好吧，我们到了。
This is where we part company.
这是我们分手的地方。
Beyond this point
lies only death.
超越这一点
谎言只有死亡。
Plus, I clock out at 6:00.
Have fun.
另外，我 6:00 下班。
玩得开心。
Danger, huh?
危险吧？
Nothing will stop us
from flipping
没有什么能阻止我们
从翻转
delicious Krabby Patties.
美味的蟹肉饼。
Oooh.
哦。
Whoa.
哇哦。
Oh.
哦。
Oh! Ohh!
哦！哦！
Ahh, all better now.
啊，现在好多了。
Oh, uh, sorry to disturb
your sacred snoring ritual,
噢，呃，抱歉打扰
你神圣的打鼾仪式，
but I have traveled a long way
但我已经走了很长的路
from the kitchen of
the Krusty Krab just to get--
从厨房
蟹堡王只是为了——
Say no more.
不多说了。
Guru Greasetrap already knows
why SpongeBob is here.
油夹大师已经知道了
为什么海绵宝宝在这里。
We have just what you need,
我们正好有您所需要的，
melon ballers,
spaghetti spoons, egg timers,
瓜球手，
意大利面勺、煮蛋计时器、
and there's also a special
on this giant banana hanger.
还有一个特别的
在这个巨大的香蕉架上。
What do you say?
你怎么说？
This is all really nice,
这一切真的很美好，
but I just need to get
my beloved spatula fixed.
但我只需要得到
我心爱的锅铲修好了。
Can you reforge it?
你能重铸它吗？
Oh, please tell me we can
save her, Mr. Greasetrap.
哦，请告诉我我们可以
救救她吧，油夹先生。
Oh, is that all? Sure.
哦，就这些了吗？当然。
It'll just take a few minutes.
只需几分钟。
Just let the old man grab
his ol' hammer and anvil.
就让老头子抢吧
他的老锤子和铁砧。
Oh. Let me get it for ya.
哦。让我给你拿一下。
No, wait.
不，等等。
Ahh!
- Don't worry.
啊！
- 不用担心。
I'll get you out of there.
我会带你离开那里。
Greasetrap cannot reforge
your spatula
捕油器无法重铸
你的抹刀
until my hands have healed up.
直到我的手痊愈为止。
But your true spatula
is inside you.
但你真正的铲子
就在你的内心。
Uh, hmm...
呃，嗯...
Mm.
毫米。
Ohh, fine.
哦，好吧。
I can teach you to reforge it.
我可以教你重铸它。
Ahh!
啊！
Thank you, Master.
Oh, thank you.
谢谢师父。
哦，谢谢。
Remember,
every cut is sacred.
请记住，
每一次切割都是神圣的。
Yo!
哟！
Dah!
呸！
Eh...
呃……
Do not carry the wood;
let the wood carry you.
请勿搬运木材；
让木头载着你。
Eh-eh... whoa!
呃呃……哇！
Ahh! Ohh!
啊！哦！
Augh!
啊啊！
Become one with the fire.
与火合而为一。
Uh-uh.
呃呃。
Eh-eh-eh, eh-eh-eh,
eh, eh...
呃呃呃呃呃呃呃
呃，呃……
whoo!
哇！
Uh...
呃...
Ahh!
I'm one with the fire.
啊！
我与火是一体的。
Ahh! Oh! Oh!
啊！哦！哦！
Ugh!
啊!
Um, Master, is it time yet?
呃，主人，时间到了吗？
Ohh, he'll never be ready.
哦，他永远不会准备好。
- I'm ready. I'm ready,
- Huh?
- 我准备好了。我准备好了，
- 啊？
I'm ready.
I'm ready. I'm ready.
我准备好了。
我准备好了。我准备好了。
- You know what?
- What?
- 你知道吗？
- 什么？
You convinced me.
你说服了我。
Greasetrap
also thinks you're ready.
隔油池
也认为你已经准备好了。
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- 真的吗？
- 嗯嗯。
Hear that, Spatty?
听到了吗，斯帕蒂？
It is finally time.
终于到了时间。
Oh... oh...
哦...哦...
Mm...
毫米...
Uh-uh.
呃呃。
Eee-hee!
诶嘿嘿！
Mwah!
You're finally back...
哇！
你终于回来了...
Finally indeed.
最后确实如此。
Thank you from the bottom
of my pants, Master.
从心底感谢你
我的裤子，主人。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
I have to find a way back
to the Krusty Krab
我必须找到回去的路
到蟹堡王
before it's too late.
以免为时已晚。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
Guru Greasetrap
knows a shortcut.
集油大师
知道一条捷径。
Close your eyes.
闭上你的眼睛。
Oooh, I love surprises.
哦，我喜欢惊喜。
Surprise.
惊喜。
Waaaaah!
哇啊啊！
Ahh.
啊。
Ah! Ah!
啊!啊!
Whoa-oh-oh, oh-oh-oh-oh-oh.
哇哦哦哦哦哦哦哦哦。
Huh?
- Ahh!
啊？
- 啊！
Amazing.
惊人的。
- Huh?
- Whoa-oh-oh-oh.
- 啊？
- 哇哦哦哦。
Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa.
哇-哇-哇-哇-哇-哇。
Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa,
whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa.
哇-哇-哇-哇-哇-哇，
哇-哇-哇-哇。
Hmm.
唔。
Time's up.
The job's yours, SpongeTom.
时间到了。
海绵汤姆，这份工作是你的了。
Oh, boy.
哦，男孩。
My dreams
are finally coming true.
我的梦想
终于实现了。
Oh!
哦！
SpongeBob.
I knew you'd be back, boy-o.
海绵宝宝。
我就知道你会回来的，小伙子。
And I'm not alone.
我并不孤单。
SpongeBob's back, everybody.
大家好，海绵宝宝回来了。
Yay.
耶。
Ooh. Ow.
哦。噢。
Eh, uhh, eh, ah.
呃呃呃呃啊。
It's our time to shine.
是我们发光发热的时候了。
Ahh!
啊！
Remember, your true spatula
is inside you.
记住，你真正的铲子
就在你的内心。
Ohh. Hmm.
哦。唔。
Mm-hmm.
嗯嗯。
Become one with the patties.
与肉饼合而为一。
Yah!
啊！
Every cut is sacred.
每一次切割都是神圣的。
Gah-gah-gah-gah-gah-gah-gah.
嘎嘎嘎嘎嘎嘎嘎嘎嘎。
Let the patties carry you.
让肉饼带你。
Mmm.
嗯。
Yay!
耶！
all: Yay!
全体：耶！
Ow.
噢。
SpongeBob,
that was amazing.
海绵宝宝，
太棒了。
Thanks, Mr. Krabs.
谢谢，蟹老板。
One Krabby Patty
and a large--hmm?
一份蟹肉饼
还有一个大——嗯？
What happened to your hands?
你的手怎么了？
I remembered
what you told me,
我记得
你告诉我的
and I went deep within
to find my true spatula.
我深入内心
找到我真正的抹刀。
Ohh.
哦。
When I said your true spatula
was inside you,
当我说你真正的铲子时
就在你内心，
I meant it was literally
inside you.
我的意思是字面上的意思
在你里面。
Ohh. It's beautiful.
哦。很美丽。
You might want
to wash that first.
你可能想要
先洗那个。